Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
It's been two months since we left Iscandar.
And it's been eight months since the Yamato left Earth.
On our journey, we've lost many friends, and there's been much sadness.
But we have never lost hope.
And that's because people on Earth
believed in us, and were waiting for us.
The last time we came this way, we were very scared.
But this time, it's different.
The Yamato is heading home, carrying hope with it.
Chuya Nakahara Poems
Balun? What do you mean?
I understand! We're using the subspace gate.
Yup.
But didn't we destroy it?
The gate back to our galaxy should still be safe.
It's well worth checking out.
That gate will take us 60,000 light years in a single jump.
We can use the controller from the last time, too.
I see... If this works, we can compensate for the time we've lost.
Tactical Officer!
I'm reading a possible mayday.
This... This is Garmillan!
We're back.
Allied fleet approaching.
It's Minister Talan.
We've been awaiting your return.
And your brother?
Ah...
With Desler gone, uniting to rebuild our home will be difficult.
Indeed.
Hope still remains.
What worries me is that some ships
rebelled and ignored your order to return.
I know.
I've sent someone I can trust.
All this time, I, Goer, have led a fleet of 3,000 forward, night and day.
And along the way, we've abandoned those that allied with the traitor Ditz.
And with thirty of my best ships,
I have wandered the infinite galaxies to finally meet you again!
I am so greatly overjoyed at—
But why do you obsess over that ship?
I want that ship.
What...?
To turn those who drove me to the brink, into my own power.
Would you not think that splendid?
The glory of Great Garmillas shall bring order and salvation to the universe.
And I alone can make that possible.
It appears to be having engine trouble and can't fly.
This is the medic. We've located survivors.
Approaching now to rescue them.
It's a Garmillas officer, right?
She says she knows them, but is sending Mori alone really okay?
It's fine.
We don't need to worry about her.
You're right.
This has happened before, hasn't it?
Though we were in opposite positions.
We'll repair your ship, and you can get back to Garmillas...
That planet...
I have no intention of returning to that planet.
My home is gone.
We, the people of Jirel, were telepaths by nature.
The people of the neighboring planets feared, envied, and destroyed us.
And Mirenel and I...
He saved you.
I understand how you feel, but Desler died in that battle...
You're lying!
He needs me!
He can't die... He can't die without me...
Warp complete. We've arrived at Balun.
This is...
The planet is...
It probably couldn't withstand the gravitational shift
after the plant at its core was destroyed.
There's a lot of debris. Shima, watch the navigation.
Roger.
Decelerate. Red 20.
We've sighted the Yamato.
It's heading for the Geschtam gate.
How are the engineers doing?
Transmitting power to the system satellite!
But we won't last much longer.
Don't worry. You only have to last long
enough to get the Yamato through the gate.
Those foolish rats don't know it's a trap.
We've sighted the subspace gate to our galaxy.
There's no damage to its external structure.
Activate the gate controller.
Activating gate controller phase 1.
It activated!
Yeah, we can do this!
What?
Enemy attack!
They waited among the debris to ambush us!
Weapons Officer, counterattack!
No, deploy the shield. We'll head straight through!
More power to engines!
Roger!
Enemy is accelerating.
They're making for the Geschtam Gate.
You've fallen for it, Yamato! Chase them into the gate!
0.2 light seconds until we reach the gate!
Torpedoes from the front! They're on a collision course!
Allied torpedoes!
Wh-What? What's going on?
This is what's going on.
The dimensional submarine!
You ignored Admiral Ditz's command to return,
and moved your fleet without orders.
There's an order for your arrest, General Goer.
A military tribunal awaits you.
The Captain seems to be having a good time.
Dogs of Ditz... Fire! Sink them!
Captain, we're ready to dive!
Not just yet... Draw them in a while longer.
Enemy submarine has passed our port side.
Garmillans fighting each other?
What's happening?
Don't let this chance pass!
Forward! Accelerate to speed 2!
Advance gate controller phase 2.
Heyni, dive now.
What's wrong?
Engine trouble!
We can't dive!
And it was just getting good.
Engine room to command!
We've opened the dimensional emergency valves.
We're ready to go!
We've lost the dimensional submarine!
The filthy dogs...
Show yourselves, cowards!
"Cowards," he says.
He's one to talk, isn't he?
You've got that right.
Who do you think I am?
I am Goer... Garemud Goer!
Mission complete.
But that scared me for a minute.
He's a useful guy to have around.
The new kid from Zartz?
Well done!
Our Captain loves to take in the abandoned dogs.
We're returning to base.
Zar Belk!
We're inside the subspace corridor.
Steady as she goes.
Did we lose them?
Well, radar won't work within the gate...
What happened, Shima?
I don't know... The helm just...
Switch to optical combat mode.
This is the launch hangar! Enemy troops are inside the ship!
Multiple hostiles on deck 02!
No response from launch hangar!
Air pressure is dropping inside the ship!
Seal the bulkheads! Kodai!
I'll command our defense!
All crew, prepare for boarding!
Arm yourselves, and prepare to repel boarders.
I'm sorry we can't put you anywhere better, but stay here, okay?
Damn it!
There are too many!
Take this, Garmies!
All right!
Oh, crap! Run!
It hurts...
Toyama?
Iwata! Toyama!
Damn it all!
Teams 1 and 2 will take over the engine room!
Send the rest of the troops to the bridge.
Yes, sir.
It appears to be going well, Talan.
I'll leave this to you.
Your Lordship, where are you going?
I'm just going to have a word with the Captain.
Protect His Lordship!
XO, there are no life signs among the troops that have boarded us.
So we're fighting Garmilloids? Then...
Then let's use it.
Yes, do it.
Analyzer, come with me.
Die, Garmies!
Who is your commander?
Tactical Officer!
Are you okay?
You saved us!
Kodai! More boarders on deck 4!
Got it!
More boarders have attacked deck 4!
Security is to head there at once and eliminate them!
My my...
The princess of Iscandar.
Or should I call you the false princess?
You're...
He's safe! He's safe!
I am honored to see you again.
Take me to the Captain.
The Captain wouldn't meet with the likes of you!
A strong-willed princess...
Your Lordship!
Your Lordship...
It's that upstart Jirel woman.
She released sympathetic waves the moment she saw him. How rude.
That's the problem with Jirels.
Get over here, old man!
Stop it! What if you hit the engine?
Why?
She loved you so much... Why?
There was no need for Earth or Garmillas to fight!
They could've cared for one another...
They could've loved one another!
They could have...
War is...
...necessary.
To force worlds to obey, and bring salvation to the universe.
And to the sole woman I love...
The woman you love?
Yuki?
Yuki!
Are you okay, Yuki?
Kodai!
Your Lordship!
Are you all right?
Stop this, Your Lordship.
I always...
Witch!
No!
Y-Yuki!
Setup complete.
Activate!
They're releasing the lock!
At this rate, the Wave Motion Core will...
Curse them!
A virus!
The mechanical soldiers are out of control!
Move!
The data we took before came in handy...
We should thank Alter.
This way.
Yuki! Yuki!
Don't shoot.
Your Lordship, hurry...
"Your Lordship"?
That's...
His Lordship has returned. We're taking off.
Fool! Who ordered you to attack?
I'm s-sorry...
Anyway, in this place, normal beam weapons...
They won't work, yes?
You're all right.
But the Desler Cannon...
The enemy ship is falling back! It's at six o'clock!
If it can't use beam weapons, then it's their Wave Motion Gun?
Energy charge! 90 belas until criticality!
Stop this! Using the Desler Cannon inside the corridor is suicide!
Do not interfere, Talan.
Your Lordship...
I am at war.
The target is turning around.
Energy charge complete.
Prepare to fire the Desler Cannon!
Target locked!
What's going on?
Cannon shells!
The enemy is firing at us with cannon shells!
Barbarians!
I will save the universe.
Just like I promised you back then...
For you...
We're through the subspace gate!
We're at our galaxy's outer rim!
Yuki... Wake up!
Don't die!
Kodai,
Please Yuki, come back...
Come back to me, Yuki... Yuki!
Yuki!
Episode 25
The Forever War
This star is the only one
If you look for something so beautiful
It is not something you can see
You will find it inside anyone
Love is the answer
Sorrow and strife
May cloud the blue sky
The overlapping warmth
Becomes a light to illuminate the world
A wish to the infinite universe
All is forgiven
And we all laugh together
Not a trick of the eye
But a dream from the bottom of my heart
No matter what tomorrow brings
Walk on
If you have nothing special
Only the strength to yearn for it
Bound to the limits of time
Create the trace of a miracle
A wish to the infinite universe
All is forgiven
And we all laugh together
Not a trick of the eye
A dream from the bottom of my heart
No matter what tomorrow brings
Walk on
Together with you
Forever
An epic journey.
A long, long voyage.
The Yamato returns to its home galaxy,
and its journey is about to end.
New life is born as other lives come to an end.
This is not goodbye, but a new meeting.
Dreaming of the green hills of Earth...
Last Episode: Memories of the Blue Planet.
The journey will never end.